So what you just saw was an ephemeral app, as it's called, which means just a temporary app that you're
방금 보신 건 임시 앱입니다 임시 앱이란 뜻으로 배포할
just using for, for, for testing before finally picking an app to deploy.
앱을 선택하기 전에 테스트에만 사용하죠
And we're going to stay with the ephemeral apps for a little bit longer, because we're now going to
비트는 좀 더 오래 사용할 겁니다 왜냐하면
take our proprietary model that we built last time and deploy that as an ephemeral app before we we
지난 시간에 만든 독점 모델을 실제로 사용하기 전에 비트로 배포할 거니까요
So in order to do that, let me show you this other file here called Pricer ephemeral.py, which is
그러기 위해서 다른 파일을 보여드릴게요 Pricer ephemeral이죠 파이썬 을 이용한 모듈인파이에는 유사점이
a Python module which is going to have some similarities with what you just saw, but with one key difference,
있습니다 그러나 한 가지 중요한 차이점이 있습니다 llama3을
which is instead of using llama 3.1, we're going to use our own fine tuned model using very similar
이용하는 것 대신에 말이죠 첫째, 정교하게 튜닝된 모델을 사용할 겁니다
code to the code that we used in the codelab when we were running our model in inference, when we were
추론하기 위해 모델을 실행하고 테스트할 때 Codelab에서 사용했던 것과 아주 유사한 코드를
testing it, and had the wonderful moment when it when it did so well.
사용해서요 아주 잘 작동하는 순간은 정말 황홀했죠
So in this, uh, Python module, then we begin as before by importing modal.
파이썬 모듈에서는 이전처럼 모드 가져오기로 시작하죠
And again I will remove volume.
그리고 다시 볼륨을 제거할게요
At one point I was going to use that, but I ended up not.
한때는 그걸 사용하려고 했는데 결국 안 했어요
So you set up, you say that you have an app.
그래서 설정하고 앱이 있다고 하죠
It's called Pricer.
프라이서라는 거예요
That's going to be the name of the app you saw.
여러분이 보신 앱의 이름이 될 거예요
Pricer.
프라이서예요
You saw my deployed version of Pricer before.
배포된 Pricer 버전을 전에 보셨죠
Um, and now we create an image and we install the same packages.
이제 이미지를 생성하고 같은 패키지를 설치해요
But wait, there's a new package.
잠깐만요, 새 소포가 왔어요
You'll remember the parameter efficient fine tuning package that we need in order to be able to load
매개 변수 효율 미세 튜닝 패키지를 기억하실 겁니다 미세 튜닝과 비밀을
in our fine tuned weights and our secrets.
로드하기 위해 필요한 거죠
Hopefully you found your way to adding them in and you should put them under HF secret.
여러분이 추가하는 방법을 찾았길 바랍니다 HF 시크릿으로 입력하세요
Or if you put it under something else, then obviously change the name here.
또는 다른 곳에 Put을 하면 여기 이름을 바꾸죠
That's the name of the the the category of secrets.
그게 비밀의 범주 이름이에요
And then within that you have to have the exactly the usual um, hugging HF underscore token for, for
그 안에 일반적인 HF_토큰을 가지고 있어야 합니다. 토큰 자체를 위한 포옹의
the token itself.
밑줄이죠.
Um, see if that's actually in the code somewhere.
코드 어딘가에 있는지 찾아봐요
Um, I don't think it is.
아닌 것 같아요
Um, anyways, so so if that hopefully that that that makes sense.
어쨌든, 그게 말이 됐으면 좋겠네요
Um, so, um, we then um, specify we want a t4 GPU.
t4 GPU를 원한다고 명시해요
We specify the base model of course.
기본 모델을 지정하죠
Llama 3.18 billion.
라마 3요 180억 달러요
Uh, the project name.
프로젝트 이름요
This is because we're going to be pulling it from the Hugging Face hub.
H깅 페이스 허브에서 끌어오기 때문이죠
Uh, so this is my hugging face username.
포옹하는 얼굴 닉네임이에요
If you want to use my trained version, then keep my name there.
훈련받은 버전을 쓰고 싶으면 내 이름을 그대로 둬요
If you want to use your version because you fine tune the version and maybe you made it even better.
자신의 버전을 쓰고 싶다면요 미세 조정해서 더 좋게 만들었을 수도 있으니까요
Maybe you've done some hyperparameter optimization and you have beaten me, in which case you should
hyperpaameter 최적화를 했다가 저를 이겼을 수도 있죠 그럴 경우
definitely use year one instead.
반드시 1년도를 사용해야 해요
Um, but this is mine, and if you use mine, then you should use that run name.
하지만 이건 제 거니까 제 걸 쓰시면 그 런네임을 쓰셔야죠
And this revision number, which you'll remember, was the epoch where I got the best results before
기억하시겠지만 이 수정 수치는 과도해지기 전이 가장 좋은
it started to overfit.
시절이었어요
And so this ends up with the fine tuned model name.
미세 튜닝 모델 이름이 되는 거죠
And so we have a simple function price.
간단한 함수 가격도 있고요
And it's a function which is almost identical to the function that we had in the Google Colab.
구글 콜랍에 있는 기능과 거의 똑같은 함수예요
It's just we've got it sitting here on my local box, and we're going to decorate it with this decorator
여기 제 로컬 박스에 있어요 장식자로 장식할 겁니다 이 이미지 안에서
that says that we want to run it in this image with these secrets and this GPU.
실행하고 싶다고 하죠 시크릿과 GPU 안에서요
But this is all the same stuff.
하지만 이건 다 같은 거예요
We do some imports.
수입도 좀 하고요
We note the question and the prefix.
질문과 앞부분을 잘 보세요
The prompt is going to be how much does this cost to the nearest dollar.
가장 가까운 비용으로 얼마가 드는지를 질문할 거예요
Then the description of the product and then price is dollars.
제품 설명과 가격은 달러예요
And then it's going to be almost unbearable for the model not to respond with what the price is.
그러면 가격이 얼마인지 모델 측에서 반응하지 않을 수 없어요
And then here we do the quantization.
이제 여기서 퀀타이즈를 해요
We load the model as before.
아까처럼 모형을 로드해요
And this line hopefully you remember this.
이 대사를 기억하면 좋겠네요
This is where we load in the the Laura fine tuned model.
로라 파인 튜닝 모델을 실을 거예요
We provide a base model.
기본 모델을 제공하죠
We provide the name of the fine tuned model and in this case, the revision number.
미세 튜닝 모델의 이름과 이 경우에는 수정 번호를 제공하죠
You can leave that off if you're just taking the final save.
마지막 세이브만 하실 거면 그건 빼도 돼요
You don't need to take an interim point.
그럴 필요 없어요
The way that I am.
있는 그대로의 나 말이에요
This is for reproducibility.
이건 번식을 위한 거예요
So that it's the random seed is set.
무작위 씨앗이 설정된 거죠
So you get the same numbers each time we tokenize.
Get up을 할 때마다 같은 숫자가 나오죠
We then make the call dot generate to our fine tuned model and we decode.
그다음 미세 튜닝 모델에 .생산이라는 호출을 만들어 디코딩하죠
And then finally hopefully you also recognize this code.
마지막으로 이 코드도 인식하셨으면 좋겠네요
This is a bit of janky code that strips out the number, the floating point number from within the text
이건 숫자, 부동점수를 제거하는 좀 엉성한 코드예요 텍스트 안에서요 잘못된
that comes back, just in case there's an errant dollar sign or something like that, and makes sure
$ 기호가 있을 경우를 대비해서요 어떤 숫자든
we get whatever number we can, um, and returns that number, and that's all there is to it.
get 할 수 있도록 하고 그 숫자를 반환합니다 그게 다예요
It's code that should be pretty familiar to you at this point.
이 시점에서 아주 친숙한 코드죠
So now we go back here.
이제 다시 여기로 돌아가죠
Um, I did already run it because as before, because it needs to warm up.
이미 작동시켰어요 예열해야 하니까요
It takes a couple of minutes.
몇 분 걸려요
So it will be agonizing if we had to wait each time.
매번 기다려야 한다면 괴로울 거예요
But I already ran it.
벌써 조회했어요
This is, of course, what I ran.
물론 제가 뛰었던 곳이죠
You say you don't need to actually have this with modal enable output.
출력 활성화 모듈이 필요 없다고 말씀하셨는데요
But if you if you don't do that there's lots of other stuff prints.
하지만 그렇게 하지 않으면 다른 프린트도 많아요
So this is a way to make it so that it's a nice and neat.
이렇게 하면 깔끔하고 멋지게 만들 수 있어요
Um, but you do need to have with app dot run.
하지만 app.lan은 있어야 해요
Um, and then I just say result is priced remote.
그리고 결과물은 가격 매기는 원격이라고 하죠
And then what I'm asking for is to price a particular object, um, that, uh, just, uh, looking
그리고 특정 객체의 가격을 매겨달라고 요청합니다. 그냥 둘러보면서 가격을 매겨달라고
around for something that I could ask it to price.
요청하는 거죠.
And the object that I've asked it to price is the very microphone that I am talking into right here.
가격을 매겨달라고 한 객체는 바로 이 마이크예요
So I just typed it in there.
그래서 그냥 입력했어요
I remember how much it cost.
얼마였는지 기억해요
And so why not?
안 될 거 없죠
Let's see how it does estimating that.
어떻게 계산되는지 보죠
Uh, so I ran it.
그래서 조회해 봤죠
It did take a couple of minutes.
몇 분 걸렸죠
Now it takes a couple of minutes because it has to warm up that box, uh, and, and populate things,
이제 몇 분 걸려요 상자를 데워야 하고 내용물도 채워야 하니까요 Colab으로
um, because it has to do everything you can imagine you'd have to do if you ran this in Colab.
실행했을 때 해야 할 모든 일을 해야 하니까요
It has to download from the Huggingface hub and then load it into memory.
H깅페이스 허브에서 다운로드 받아 메모리에 로드해야 해요
Um, it also has to pip install all of those packages.
또한 모든 패키지를 설치해야 하죠
So there's a lot that has to happen, which is why it takes a bit of time.
비트를 만들려면 할 일이 많아서 시간이 좀 걸려요
Um, and it did all this stuff and at the end it completed and it returned the number one, 33, $133.
그 모든 걸 다 하고 마지막에 1을 반환했어요 33, 133달러
And I think that is round about what this costs.
이 작품의 가격은 대략 그 정도예요
So, uh, yeah, it's, uh, I think that's pretty much, uh, a spot on, uh, so maybe it was it.
네, 꽤 정확한 위치인 것 같아요 그래서 맞을지도 몰라요
Who knows?
누가 알겠어요?
It could have been in the training data set, but but, uh, certainly a nice result.
훈련 데이터 세트에도 있을 수 있지만 좋은 결과예요
So hopefully you're doing this to you're trying this.
여러분도 이렇게 해 보세요
You will have to wait those two, two, three minutes.
2-3분 정도 기다려야 해요
You'll be able to go onto modal while you're doing it, and you'll be able to go to ephemeral apps.
작업하는 동안 Modal로 갈 수도 있고 단기 앱으로 갈 수도 있어요
It's no longer running, but while it was running, it will have been here, and you'll be able to watch
지금은 실행 중이지만 실행 중일 때는 여기
it and see it doing its thing and then, uh, get a satisfactory result.
있을 겁니다. 그리고 작업을 하는 것을 볼 수 있고 만족스러운 결과를 얻을 수 있죠.
Okay.
네
But now we've done that, it's time to make the transition from these ephemeral apps, which is just
이제 그건 끝났고 짧은 앱에서 전환할 차례입니다 원격으로
ways of running functions remotely.
기능을 실행하는 방법이죠
Now we're going to have deployed apps, which is when we tell Modell that we've got some functionality
배포된 앱이 있는데 Modell에 기능성 몇 개를 영구적으로
and we want to have it be, um, permanently sitting on.
포함하고 싶다고 말할 때죠
Modell will still only pay for it when we actually run it, but we do want to give it a sort of a name
Modell은 여전히 실행할 때만 지불합니다 하지만 이름 같은
and a proper place where we can quickly get back to it if we need to.
걸 정하고 싶어요 필요할 경우 재빨리 다시 할 수 있는 적절한 장소도요
Um, and the way you do it is on the command line, you type model.deploy and then the name of the app
명령줄에 모델을 입력하는 게 그 방법이에요 배포하고 배포하려는 앱 이름을
that you want to deploy.
입력해요
Uh, and it's important to note that this this really this is the moment that we are taking some code,
중요한 건 바로 지금 이 순간 우리가 데이터 과학자로서 만든 코드나
some model that we have built as data scientists, and we are deploying it in a way that can be used
모델을 생산 목적으로 사용할 수 있는 방식으로 배포하고 있다는
for production purposes.
거예요
It's going to have a Python API behind it.
파이썬 API가 뒤에 있을 거예요
People will be able to call it, um, from Python and be able to to invoke our API.
파이썬 을 이용해서 호출할 수 있고 API 호출도 할 수 있어요
And this is an example of productionizing, something that we've built in originally in JupyterLab.
이건 프로덕션화의 예입니다 원래 주피터랩에서 구축한 거죠
Um, it can also modal also allows you to build Rest endpoints very easily so that it doesn't need to
Modal 또한 REST 끝점을 아주 쉽게 빌드할 수 있게 해줍니다 파이썬으로 호출할
be called by Python.
필요가 없죠
It could just be called from any any HTTP query.
어떤 HTTP 쿼리에서도 호출될 수 있어요
Um, we're not going to cover that in this class because everything we're doing is in Python.
이 수업에선 다루지 않겠습니다 파이썬 으로만 다루고 있으니까요
So we might as well just just call it from Python.
그러니 그냥 파이썬 에서 호출하는 게 낫겠어요
Um, but it's very easy to do and the docs are super clear about it.
하지만 아주 쉽고 의사들도 명확하게 알려줬어요
So, uh, one thing I glossed over a moment ago, you may know this already.
제가 방금 얼버무린 게 있는데 이미 아실지도 모르겠네요
Uh, Jupiter, uh, has this great feature that if you want to, you can run something in terminal just
주피터에는 이런 멋진 기능이 있어요 터미널에서 뭔가를 실행할 수 있죠
by doing an exclamation mark.
느낌표만 찍으면 돼요
And then the the name of the command you want to run.
실행하고 싶은 명령의 이름을 적고요
You can also actually open up a terminal window by pressing the plus button there and, and create a
터미널 윈도우를 열 수 있습니다 플러스 버튼을 눌러서 터미널을 생성할
terminal.
수 있죠
Uh, but this is even easier because you can do it right in the prompt here, which I did above.
하지만 이게 훨씬 더 쉬워요 여기 프롬프트에서 할 수 있거든요 제가 위에서 한 거죠
And the command again is modal deploy and then the package name.
명령은 역시 양식 배포와 패키지 이름이죠
So it's priceless service.
값을 매길 수 없는 서비스죠
So let's go and have a look at this package called Price of Service.
그럼 프라이스 오브 서비스라는 패키지를 살펴보죠
Let me quickly tell you what I've got here.
여기 뭐가 있는지 간단히 말씀드릴게요
So uh it's, uh, remarkably, uh, similar.
놀랍게도 비슷하네요
Um, you can see that basically we, we have, uh, the, the constants, we define the function, uh,
보시다시피 기본적으로 상수가 있고 함수를 정의합니다
and uh, it's basically the same thing, but this is going to be enough to deploy, uh, our code as
기본적으로 같은 거지만 우리 코드를 서비스로 적절하게 배포하기에
a service, as a, as a proper deployed service, rather than the ephemeral version of the process that
충분합니다 이전 프로세스의 일시적인 버전 말고요
Um, but yeah, it is the same thing.
네, 같은 거예요
It's the identical code just packaged differently.
같은 코드인데 다르게 포장돼 있어요
And again, with this volume that's not required.
이 볼륨으로는 필요 없어요
Uh, uh, so on running that if we go back to the day one notebook, uh, you'll see that it deployed
실행해 보죠 첫째 날 공책으로 돌아가면 Price Services로
it to as Price's service.
배포된 게 보이시죠
Um, it gives me a little URL at the end of it.
끝에 작은 URL이 뜨네요
Um, and then once it's done that if I go now back here and I go to deployed apps, you'll see that
그게 완료되면 이제 여기로 돌아가서 배포된 앱으로 가면 가격이 실행되고
price is running there.
있는 게 보이시죠
Um, sitting on a T4 GPU box, just as we specified.
T4 GPU 박스에 앉아서요 명시한 대로요
If we come back here, the way that you call a deployed app is different and actually simpler than the
다시 돌아와서 보면 배포된 앱을 호출하는 방법은 에피헤머럴 앱과 다르고 사실 더
ephemeral app.
간단해요
You don't need that.
그건 필요 없어요
That, um, scaffolding you saw a moment ago.
방금 보신 비계 말이에요
Instead you just say modal dot function, dot lookup, and then you give the name of the service and
Modal.comcom과 .outup을 입력하는 대신 서비스 이름을 입력하고
then the name of the of the function.
함수 이름을 입력해요
Simple as that.
간단해요
Modal dot function.
Modal. 함수요
Dot lookup the service and the function.
.찾기 서비스와 함수요
Um, and so once you've run that you can then say price dot remote and make the, the remote call.
실행이 끝나면 가격. remote을 치고 원격 호출을 해요
And we get back the same number 133.
그리고 아까와 같은 133을 얻게 돼요. Get up! Get up!
And that's all there is to it.
그게 다인 거죠
We've just deployed an app with our proprietary model to the cloud, and we've called it and it's run
클라우드에 소유 모델을 이용해 앱을 배포했고 클라우드에서 실행되도록 이름을
on the cloud.
붙였어요
Uh, now there is a nicer way of doing this, a fancier way of doing this.
더 멋지고 더 멋진 방법이 있어요
When we build it this way, every time that it goes to sleep and needs to be warmed back up again,
이렇게 만들면 잠들었다가 다시 따뜻하게 해 줘야 해요 그런데
which, by the way, is quite quickly like after a minute or two it goes to sleep.
1-2분 정도 지나면 금방 잠들어 버리죠
And so every time you call it, you're waiting all that extra time, uh, and basically every time it
그래서 전화를 걸 때마다 추가 시간을 기다려야 하고 이미지를
has to rebuild an image and do the imports and load the model and so on.
다시 구축하고 모델을 불러오는 등의 작업을 해야 하죠
Um, sorry.
죄송해요
I jumped to the version where it doesn't have to do that.
그럴 필요가 없는 버전이 됐죠
Here we go.
시작할게요
This is the bad version where it has to do all of that.
이건 나쁜 버전이에요 그 모든 걸 해야 하죠
So I've made a second version of it.
그래서 두 번째 버전을 만들었어요
Prices service two pi.
가격은 2파이예요
This module, uh, and this one is done a bit in a smarter way.
이 모듈은 좀 더 비트 있게 진행되는데요
It's done using a class, and it's done in a way that allows you to pre-build some, uh, some aspects
클래스를 이용하고 초기화의 몇 가지 측면을 미리 빌드할 수 있게 해
of initialization.
줘요
So you don't need to do it every time.
매번 안 해도 돼요
Um, so when you define a class like this, you have the ability to use this decorator model dot build
클래스를 이렇게 정의할 때 장식자 모델.빌드를 사용할 수 있고 처음 만들어졌을
and write a function that will populate your box the first time that it's built.
때 여러분의 박스를 채울 함수를 쓸 수 있어요
And in this case I download from huggingface the model and I put it in the cache.
이 경우엔 HINGPace 모델에서 다운로드 받아 캐시에 넣었어요
And I'm not going to walk through this in detail, because I'm going to leave that as an exercise for
자세히 설명하진 않겠습니다 시간 관계상
you in the interest of time, but it's perfectly self-explanatory.
연습 삼아 남겨두겠습니다만 아주 간단하죠
This code will load the files from Huggingface and put it in Huggingface cache.
이 코드는 허깅페이스에서 파일을 불러와 허깅페이스 캐시에 놓죠
And then you can have this decorator modal dot enter, and this is when the function actually gets called.
그리고 Modal.엔터를 장식할 수 있죠 함수가 호출될 때예요
And this is where it's going to set things up by setting up a tokenizer and setting up a base model
여기서 설정합니다 토큰라이저를 설정하고 베이스 모델을 설정해 한 번
that will be loaded once.
로드하죠
So it can be used repeatedly.
반복적으로 사용할 수 있죠
If this is called before it goes to sleep.
잠들기 전에 부르면요
Uh, and this is the method itself price.
이 방법 자체가 가격이에요
This is now the same as before, but the the code to load the model into memory has been pulled out
이전과 같지만 메모리에 모델을 로드하는 코드는 여기 여기로 나왔어요 Modal in Setting으로요
into this one here into modal into setup under the the A decorator modal or enter.
a Decoator Modal or enter 밑에서요
And so as a result of all of this, if I haven't lost you yet with this, when I go back to day one,
이 모든 것의 결과로 아직 이것과 관련해 여러분이 이해를 못 하신다면 첫날로
the key point, uh, I then do a modal deploy of process service two.
돌아가서 핵심 포인트를 말씀드리자면 프로세스 서비스 2의 배포 양식을 할 거예요
So process service two gets deployed.
프로세스 서비스 2가 배포되었어요
And when I've done that I can then use this code slightly different.
그렇게 하고 나면 이 코드를 약간 다르게 사용할 수 있어요
You remember this is what we did last time we did modal dot function dot lookup.
지난번에 했던 거 기억하시죠 Modal. 함수 .조회를 했죠
Now we do modal dot class which annoyingly is spelt cls.
Modal.Crice는 짜증 나게도 cls로 쓰였어요
Um they probably class is probably something that is already used.
클래스는 이미 사용된 걸 거예요
So they couldn't use that.
그래서 못 썼죠
So modal dot dot dot lookup and then price of service and price now with a capital P price.
Modal.dot.lup 서비스 가격과 P로 시작하는 가격이요
So it's the class.
수업이 문제군요
So this will will find the class that we've just just deployed.
방금 배포한 클래스를 찾을 거예요
You can instantiate that class.
그 클래스를 인스턴스화할 수 있어요
So I say price is is an instance of price.
가격은 가격의 예시라고 하죠
And then I can call Pricer dot price dot remote.
Pricer.pice.triter라고 호출할 수 있어요
Uh and when I do that, I get back that answer again.
get을 입력하면 그 답이 다시 나오죠
And when I ran this before, it ran super fast because it was already in memory, but now it's probably
전에 실행했을 때 아주 빠르게 실행되었어요 이미 메모리에 있었으니까요 하지만 지금은 아마 이미 바뀌었을
swapped out already.
거예요
So yeah, I won't do it now to avoid holding us up, because we'll press on to the final example, which
네, 지연되는 걸 피하려면 지금은 안 하겠습니다 마지막 예제로 넘어갈 테니까요
I will run.
실행할 거예요
Um, I'm going to kick it off now so that I can talk while it's doing its thing.
지금 시작할게요 기계가 작동하는 동안 얘기 좀 하게요
We'll let it run.
이대로 둘게요
So I have packaged this into a nice, useful class called Specialist Agent, which is our first agent
그래서 이걸 스페셜리스트 에이전트라는 유용한 클래스로 패키지했어요 우리가 살펴볼 첫 번째 에이전트죠
Um, and it is something which is going to look up our pricer running on modal and call our pricer.
모달에서 실행 중인 가격을 검색해 가격을 부를 거예요
And it's something which just takes a single function, a single method price.
단일 함수와 단일 메서드 가격만 취하는 거죠
And you can pass in what you want it to price.
원하는 가격대로 제출할 수 있어요
Let's go and look.
가서 보죠
It's in agents.
에이전트예요
And now you get your first preview.
지금 첫 번째 미리 보기가 있어요. Get up! Get up!
Look at all of the different agents that we're going to be playing with this week.
이번 주에 함께 일하게 될 모든 에이전트를 보세요
Uh, and we're going to go in and have a look at this particular agent.
이제 들어가서 이 에이전트를 살펴볼 거예요
It's called specialist agent because it's using our special model.
특수 요원이라고 불리는 건 우리 특수 모델을 사용했기 때문이죠
So this is our Python module for our specialist agent.
이건 전문 에이전트를 위한 파이썬 툴 모듈이에요
And as I promised you'll see that I've written comments and that there's some type hints going on.
약속드린 대로 코멘트도 달았고 힌트도 몇 가지 있어요
So this class is a very simple class.
이 클래스는 아주 간단해요
It's an agent that runs our fine tuned LLM remotely on modal.
우리 LLM을 원격으로 조정하는 에이전트죠
Um, it sets a name, it gives itself a name and a color.
이름과 색깔을 정하고 이름을 부여하죠
And the reason for that, you'll find out later, is that we're going to have our agents log.
그 이유는 나중에 알게 되겠지만 요원 일지가 있기 때문이죠
So we'll be able to see what they're all doing.
다들 뭘 하는지 볼 수 있게요
And the specialist agent is going to take the color red.
전문가가 빨간색을 채취할 거예요
So you'll be able to see when it's thinking and doing things and so on.
언제 생각하고 행동하는지 볼 수 있죠
Uh, so I initialize in the initialization in the constructor method here I log that, that it's getting
생성자 메서드에서 초기화를 시작했고요 로그인하면 시작되고 있죠
And I do this modal dot plus dot lookup.
Modal.+.찾기를 하고요
And I look up the price of service and the price.
서비스 비용과 가격을 찾아봤어요
And this is the thing that we just deployed a moment ago.
이건 조금 전에 우리가 배포한 거죠
So we look looked that up and we instantiate it.
그래서 찾아보고 인스턴스화했죠
And then we log that we are ready for business.
그럼 일 시작할 준비가 됐다고 기록해요
And the price call itself does exactly what we just looked at.
가격 호출 자체도 방금 본 것과 똑같아요
We do price dot price dot remote.
가격도, 가격도, 리모컨도 있어요
It's just like when we did the hello dot remote.
헬로 닷 리모컨을 만들었을 때처럼요
We're taking a function.
함수를 취하는 거예요
We're calling a remote, which means it's going to run on the cloud.
원격 조종을 호출하고 있어요 클라우드에서 실행된다는 뜻이죠
It's almost transparent to us.
우리 눈에는 거의 투명해요
It's like we're calling it directly here in Python, but it's actually going to run on the cloud on
파이썬 에서 직접 호출하는 것 같지만 사실은 우리가 명시한 T4 박스의 클라우드에서
the T4 box that we specified.
실행될 거예요
We pass in the description, we log the fact that it's completed and we return the result.
설명을 전달하고 완료됐다는 사실을 기록하고 결과를 반환하죠
So hopefully I've jabbered away for long enough that when we turn back to day one, it's going to have
제가 너무 오래 떠들었나 봐요 첫날로 돌아왔을 때 끝났거나
finished and it hasn't finished.
안 끝났길 바라요
Well then I can also fill in the time by flipping over here and we can take a look at it doing its thing.
그럼 이쪽을 뒤집어서 시간을 채울 수도 있어요 그럼 작업을 하는 걸 살펴보죠
Uh, so here now, before we remember, I got lost looking for ephemeral apps.
그래서 지금 우리가 기억하기 전에 일시적인 앱을 찾다가 길을 잃었어요
We are now correctly on deployed apps because we're looking at our Pricer service or Pricer, which
이제 제대로 배포된 앱에 있습니다 왜냐하면 Pricer 서비스를 보고 있으니까요
is a deployed app.
배포된 앱이죠
We can go into this and have a look at it.
이 안에 들어가서 살펴보죠
Oh, it's now saying succeeded.
성공했다고 뜨네요
Let's go back and have a look.
다시 가서 보죠
It has indeed succeeded.
확실히 성공했어요
There we go.
됐어요
It succeeded and it returned the right number 133.
성공적으로 133을 반환했어요
And if we run it again right away without delay, see how quick it is?
지체 없이 바로 다시 실행하면 얼마나 빠른지 보이죠?
That's how quick it normally is when it's already warm.
이미 따뜻할 때는 보통 그 정도로 빨리 녹아요
That's going out to the cloud.
클라우드에 올릴 거예요
Let's quickly come up with something different.
빨리 다른 걸 생각해 보죠
Let's go for an iPhone SE second edition.
iPhone SE의 2차 버전을 보죠
Let's see how much an iPhone.
아이폰은 얼마죠?
There we go.
됐어요
299 bucks apparently.
299달러예요
Uh, so I'm delighted that that we got to see that and, uh, iPad Pro uh, second generation.
그래서 2세대 아이패드 프로를 볼 수 있어서 정말 기뻐요
299 again, it seems that must be a popular price.
299달러라니 인기가 많은가 보군요
So you get a good sense once it's warmed up.
get이 따뜻해지면 좋은 감각을 갖게 되죠
Once you've populated the model, you can call it very quickly and you'll get back a quick response.
모델을 일단 채우면 아주 빨리 호출할 수 있어요 빠른 응답을 얻게 되죠 get it
And again, we're calling our agent.
에이전트에게 전화했죠
And what our agent is doing is our agent over here is simply it's done this already.
에이전트가 하는 일은 여기 있는 에이전트가 하는 일은 이미 완료되었다는 거죠
It's already got the class, it's already instantiated it.
이미 클래스를 갖고 있고 인스턴스화했어요
And that class is already loaded in the files from Hugging Face.
그 클래스는 안은 얼굴 파일에 이미 로드됐어요
And it's warm and ready for business.
따뜻하고 일할 준비가 됐어요
And then when we call this method, it doesn't need to load in the files again.
이 메서드를 호출할 때 파일을 다시 로드할 필요가 없어요
It's got it all ready.
다 준비해 놨어요
All it needs to do is inference.
추론만 하면 돼요
And that's why it's so quick.
그래서 그렇게 빠른 거예요
And that's that's the trick.
그게 비결이에요
That's how you build an API to a model that's running in the cloud, serverless, and how you make sure
클라우드에서 실행되는 모델에 API 구축하는 방법입니다 서버리스
that you've cached the model weights in memory so that it's ready for action.
모델이죠 메모리에 모델 값을 캐시하는 방법입니다 준비되도록요
So I know we went through it very fast, but now you have to go back and do this again yourself.
아주 빠르게 진행했지만 이제 다시 돌아가서 직접 해야 해요
Make sure that you can make it work and that it looks good on modal.
제대로 작동하고 모듈에서도 멋지게 보여야 해요
And I will see you in the next video to wrap up.
그럼 다음 영상에서 마무리하도록 하죠